Preliminary Inventory of the Bund Freiheit der Wissenschaft records
Hoover Institution Archives
Bund Freiheit der Wissenschaft records,
1969-2010
91106
Hoover Institution Archives
240 manuscript boxes (128.8 linear feet)
Minutes, correspondence, memoranda, reports, financial records, press releases, printed matter, and photographs, relating to education in West Germany and reunified Germany, and especially to radicalism in German educational institutions.
Bund Freiheit der Wissenschaft.
Access
Boxes 117-122, 130-137, and 159-178 closed until 2021 March 5.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired between 1991 and 2010. An increment was added in 2011.
Accruals
Increments may have been received since this finding aid was prepared. Please check Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/ to find the full extent of the collection.
Historical Note
The Bund Freiheit der Wissenschaft was established in 1970 in West Germany to promote academic freedom. One of the organization's main activities was the publishing of journals, pamphlets, and monographs on subjects related to higher education in Germany. The organization produced several of its own journals, -including Hochschulpolitischen Informationen, Moderator, and Freiheit der Wissenschaft. In addition to these publications, the Bund Freiheit der Wissenschaft also published numerous pamphlets and monographs of German scholars affiliated with the organization. The Bund Freiheit der Wissenschaft also hosted regular forums on topics related to education and higher education reform.
Scope and Content Note
Minutes, correspondence, memoranda, reports, financial records, press releases, printed matter, and photographs, relating to education in West Germany and reunified Germany, and especially to radicalism in German educational institutions.
Conservatism.; Education--Germany (West); Education.; Germany.; Radicalism--Germany (West); Student movements--Germany (West); Universities and colleges--Germany (West)
- Photographs (Fotos), circa 1980 (Box 1)
- Bremen section (Sektionen Bremen), 1973-1987
- Bremen section (Sektionen Bremen), 1973-1987 (Box 2)
- Cologne section (Sektionen Köln), 1972-1978
- School documentation (Schuldokumentationen), 1975-1977 (Box 3)
- Persons leaving, K-Z (Austritte K-Z), 1989-1990
- Circulars (Rundschreiben 1972ff.), 1971-1974 (Box 4)
- Disput (Zeitschrift Disput), 1974-1975
- Cologne section (Sektion Köln), 1975-1979
- Board of directors meeting (Vorstand Sitzungen), 1984 (Box 5)
- Bremen section (Sektion Bremen), 1982-1984
- Board of directors meeting (Vorstand Sitzungen), 1983 (Box 6)
- Federal committee meetings (Bundesausschuss-Sitzungen), 1985-1987
- German Press Agency (Deutsche Presse-Agentur), 1997 (Box 7)
- Correspondence (Korrespondenz), 1985 (Box 8)
- German Press Agency (Deutsche Presse-Agentur), 1998
- Correspondence (Korrespondenz), 1985 (Box 9)
- German Press Agency (Deutsche Presse-Agentur), 1996
- German Press Agency (Deutsche Presse-Agentur), 1995-1996 (Box 10)
- Working group, school in North Rhine-Westphalia (Arbeitskreis Schule Nordrhein-Westfalen), 1984-1990 (Box 11)
- General meeting (Mitgliederversammlungen), 1984, 1986, 1988, 1990
- Ranking of the universities ("Ranking" der Universitäten), 1979-1988 (Box 12)
- Local representatives (Lokale Repräsentanten), 1970-1971
- German Press Agency (Deutsche Presse-Agentur), 1998 (Box 13)
- Correspondence (Korrespondenz), 1970-1971
- German Press Agency (Deutsche Presse-Agentur), 1995 (Box 14)
- Scholars' Academy, Berlin (Akademie der Wissenschaften Berlin), 1989-1990
- German state authorities (Kompetenzen der Bundesländer), 1992-1993
- Study ability (Studierfähigkeit), 1992-1993
- Association of universities and other higher education institutions in Germany (Hochschulrektorenkonferenz), 1995-1999 (Box 15)
- Correspondence (Korrespondenz), 1990-1997
- Miscellany (Verschiedenes), 1990-1994 (Box 16)
- Inquiries to the board of directors (Anfragen Vorstand), 1985-1986
- North Rhine-Westphalia (Nordrhein-Westfalen), 1996-1998
- School paper Future of the School (Schulpapier Zukunft der Schule), 1996-1998
- Research on women's issues (Frauenforschung), 1991-1997
- Minister of Education conference (Kultusministerkonferenz), 1991-1997 (Box 17)
- Photographs (Fotos), 1970-1977
- Photographs (Fotos), 1972-1975 (Box 18)
- Bund Demokratischer Wissenschaftler (Bund Demokratischer Wissenschaftler), 1981-1990
- Elite debate (Elite-Diskussion), 1984-1985
- Press releases, (Presseerklärungen), 1972-1984 (Box 18-19)
- Sections D-K (Sektionen D-K), 1979-1984 (Box 20)
- Bremen section (Sektion Bremen), 1982
- Hochschulpolitische Informationen ( Zeitschrift HPI), 1982-1983 (Box 21)
- University legal framework (Hochschulrahmengesetz), 1982
- Press commentaries on the Bund Freiheit der Wissenschaft (Pressestimmen zum BFW), 1970 (Box 22)
- Reactions to the Bund Freiheit der Wissenschaft (Reaktionen auf den BFW), 1978-1985
- Publications of the sections (Publikationen der Sektionen), 1973-1977 (Box 23)
- Bund Freiheit der Wissenschaft circulars (BFW-Rundschreiben), 1974-1977
- Bund Freiheit der Wissenschaft documents (BFW-Dokumentationen), 1974-1979 (Box 24)
- Press reviews concerning the BFW (Presseechos), 1971-1985
- Correspondence (Korrespondenz), 1972-1975 (Box 25)
- School working group, North Rhine-Westphalia (Schularbeitskreis Nordrhein-Westfalen), 1976-1977
- Cologne section (Sektion Köln), 1974-1979
- Leaflets against the Bund Freiheit der Wissenschaft (Flugblätter gegen den BFW), 1970
- Enquete Commission establishment (Enquetekommission Bildung), 1989-1991 (Box 26)
- German Press Agency (Deutsche Presse-Agentur), 1998-1999
- Länder laws (Ländergesetze), 1989-1998 (Box 27-28)
- University legal framework, 1989-1995
- CDU education policy (CDU-Bildungspolitik), 1990-1998
- General education policy (Bildungspolitik allgemein), 1993 (Box 29)
- Enquete Commission (Enquetekommission), 1987-1989
- East Germany history (DDR-Geschichte), 1992-1993
- University history (Universitätsgeschichte), 1991-1997 (Box 30)
- Association of Universities and other Higher Education Institutions in West Germany (Westdeutsche Rektorenkonferenz WRK; Hochschulrektorenkonferenz; Sektionen), 1991-1994
- Section reports (Sektionsberichte), 1974-1975
- Newspaper clippings (Zeitungsausschnitte), circa 1970s (Box 31)
- Press commentaries on the Bund Freiheit der Wissenschaft (Presse zum BFW), 1971
- Contest (Preisausschreiben), 1983-1987 (Box 32)
- Federal committee (Bundesausschuss), 1975-1978
- Circulars (Rundschreiben), 1975-1978
- Meetings (Sitzungen), 1975-1978
- High school graduation examination (Abitur/Aditur), 1983-1986 (Box 33)
- Aich's fall (Fall Aich), 1983-1986
- Bund Freiheit der Wissenschaft management (BFW-Verwaltung), 1983-1986
- Mailing lists (Versandlisten), 1983-1986
- Bund Demokratischer Wissenschaftler (Bund Demokratischer Wissenschaftler), 1972
- Cologne section (Sektion Köln), 1972
- North Rhine-Westphalia (Nordrhein-Westfalen), 1972
- University legal framework (Hochschulrahmengesetz), 1984-1985 (Box 34)
- Ranking of the universities ("Ranking" der Universitäten), 1985-1987
- Correspondence (Korrespondenz), circa 1970s (Box 35)
- "Consent" ("Zustimmung"), circa 1970s
- Board of directors and federal committee (Vorstand und Bundesausschuss), 1972
- Press regarding Bund Freiheit der Wissenschaft (Presse zum BFW), 1971
- Solicitation of donations (Mitgliederbetreutung), 1971-1982 (Box 36)
- By-laws (Satzung), 1984-1985
- Founding congress (Gründungskongress), 1970-1971
- University legal framework (Hochschulrahmengesetz), 1985-1986 (Box 37)
- Newspaper clippings (Zeitungsausschnitte), 1972
- Correspondence (Korrespondenz), 1979-1983 (Box 38)
- Board of directors meetings (Vorstandssitzungen), 1972-1975
- Bremen section (Sektion Bremen), 1977 (Box 39)
- Board of directors (Vorstand), 1972-1973
- Federal committee (Bundesausschuss), 1972-1973
- General meetings (Mitgliederversammlungen), 1972-1973
- Correspondence of the board of directors to 1973 (Korrespondenz Vorstand bis 1973), 1971-1973
- Committees (Kommissionen), 1972-1973 (Box 40)
- Boundary task force, school in North Rhine-Westphalia (Schule Nordrhein-Westfalen), 1981-1983
- Boundary task force, school in North Rhine-Westphalia (Schule Nordrhein-Westfalen), 1981-1983 (Box 41)
- "Achiever" fundraising campaign ("Erlanger" Spendenaktion), 1980-1985
- Member and board of directors correspondence (Korrespondenz Mitglieder, Vorstand), 1985-1986 (Box 42)
- Member correspondence (Korrespondenz Mitglieder), 1981-1988 (Box 43)
- Academic freedom (Wissenschaftfreiheit), 1995-1997 (Box 44)
- National working group, school in North Rhine-Westphalia (Landesarbeitskreis, Schule Nordrhein-Westfalen), 1992-1999
- Ranking of the universities ("Ranking" der Universitäten), 1989-1993
- University law Saxony-Anhalt (Universitätsgesetz Sachsen-Anhalt), 1993
- Statements to the press (Presseerklärungen), 1985-1987 (Box 45)
- National working group, school in North Rhine-Westphalia (Landesarbeitskreis Schule Nordrhein-Westfalen), 1973-1992
- Photographs (Fotos), 1968-1985 (Box 46)
- FdW Neugestaltung (Zeitschrift FdW Neugestaltung), 1975-1980
- Photographs (Fotos), 1968-1978 (Box 47)
- Student Finance (Studentenfinanzierung), 1987-1998 (Box 47-48)
- Correspondence (Korrespondenz), 1990-1993 (Box 48)
- Photographs (Fotos), 1977-1980
- Halle (Halle Korrespondenz), 1984-1995
- Schleswig-Holstein (Schleswig-Holstein Korrespondenz), 1987-1995
- Thuringia (Thüringen Korrespondenz), 1991-1998
- Statements to the press (Presseerklärungen), 1974-1978 (Box 50)
- General meeting (Mitgliederversammlung), 1978
- Bund Freiheit der Wissenschaft in the press and leaflets (BFW in Presse und Flugblättern), 1970-1977 (Box 51)
- Bund Freiheit der Wissenschaft in the press and leaflets (BFW in Presse und Flugblättern), 1970-1977
- Correspondence (Korrespondenz), 1984-1985
- Register of associations questions (Vereinsregister-Fragen), 1973-1975 (Box 52)
- Record of establishment (Gründungsprotokoll), 1970-1974
- By-law (Satzung), 1970-1974
- Founding congress participants (Teilnehmer Gründungskongress), 1970-1974
- Sections (Sektionen), 1975 (Box 53)
- University legal framework (Hochschulrahmengesetz), 1976-1987
- Sections (Sektionen), 1976 (Box 54)
- General meeting (Mitgliederversammlung), 1976
- Correspondence (Korrespondenz), 1984
- Correspondence (Korrespondenz), 1973, 1984 (Box 55)
- Bremen section (Sektion Bremen), 1974
- University legal framework drafts (Hochschulrahmengesetze entwürfe), 1988-1993 (Box 56)
- Federal Ministry for Education and Knowledge (Bundesministerium für Bildung und Wissenschaft), 1994-1999
- Sections (Sektionen), 1975-1996 (Box 57)
- Education advisory board (Wissenschaftsrat), 1993-1999
- Association of universities and other higher education institutions in Germany (Hochschulrektorenkonferenz), 1999 (Box 58)
- Minister of Education conference (Kultusministerkonferenz), 1997-1999
- Bremen section (Sektion Bremen), 1988-1992
- Federal-state committee (Bund-Länderkommission), 1992-1998
- Federal-state committee (Bund-Länderkommission), 1992-1998 (Box 59)
- Association of universities (Hochschulverband), 1989-1999
- Notgemeinschaft, 1977-1991
- Notgemeinschaft, 1991 (Box 60)
- Readers' letters (Leserbriefe), 1974-1977
- German Press Agency (Deutsche Presse-Agentur), 1999
- Press regarding Bund Freiheit der Wissenschaft (Presse zum BFW), 1972
- Press releases (Pressemitteilungen), 1973 (Box 61)
- University legal framework (Hochschulrahmengesetz), 1984-1985
- University legal framework (Hochschulrahmengesetz), 1984-1985 (Box 62)
- Board of directors meetings (Vorstandssitzungen), 1975-1978
- Federal committee meetings (Bundesausschuss Sitzungen), 1977-1990 (Box 63)
- Federal committee (Bundesausschuss), 1982-1984 (Box 64)
- Press conferences (Pressekonferenzen), 1975-1983
- FdW pinboard (FdW-Pin-Wand), 1984-1986
- Federal committee meetings (Bundesausschuss Sitzungen), 1982-1984 (Box 65)
- Bremen section (Sektion Bremen), 1985-1988
- BFW lawsuits (Prozesse BFW), 1971-1972
- BFW lawsuits (Prozesse BFW), 1971-1972 (Box 66)
- Board of directors meetings (Vorstandssitzungen), circa 1970s
- Bremen section (Sektion Bremen), 1977-1981 (Box 67)
- FdW Quellen (Zeitschrift FdW Quellen, 1983
- Activity reports (Tätigkeitsberichte), 1978-1984 (Box 68)
- German Press Agency (Deutsche Presse-Agentur), 1986-1996
- Arrangements (Veranstaltungen), 1972-1979 (Box 69)
- Cologne section (Sektion Köln), 1984
- FdW Federspitze (Zeitschrift FdW Federspitze), 1982-1986 (Box 70)
- Correspondence (Korrespondenz), 1979-1983
- Board of directors meetings (Vorstandssitzungen), 1972-1977 (Box 71)
- Cologne section (Sektion Köln), 1979-1985
- Publications (Veröffentlichungen), 1985 (Box 72)
- Cologne section (Sektion Köln), 1972-1978
- Correspondence of the board of directors (Korrespondenz Vorstand), 1975-1979
- Circulars (Rundschreiben), 1972-1973
- Bund Freiheit der Wissenschaft limited liability corporation (BFW GmbH), 1986 (Box 73)
- Cologne section (Sektion Köln), 1987
- Hochschulpolitische Informationen correspondence (Zeitschrift HPI Korrespondenz), 1972-1982 (Box 74)
- Admission requests (Aufnahmeanträge), 1971-1974
- Notgemeinschaft (Notgemeinschaft), 1977-1987 (Box 75)
- Admission requests (Aufnahmeanträge), 1972-1973
- Admission requests (Aufnahmeanträge), 1971-1974 (Box 76)
- General meetings (Mitgliederversammlungen), 1974
- General meetings (Mitgliederversammlungen), 1980 (Box 77)
- Correspondence (Korrespondenz), 1981-1984
- Press commentaries on the Bund Freiheit der Wissenschaft (Pressestimmen zum BFW), 1972 (Box 78)
- Office (Geschäftsstelle), 1974
- Persons leaving (Austritte), 1989-1990 (Box 79)
- Board of directors meetings (Vorstandssitzungen), 1972-1974
- General meetings (Mitgliederversammlungen), 1872-1974
- German Press Agency (Deutsche Presse-Agentur), 1992 (Box 80)
- Board of directors meetings (Vorstandssitzungen), 1986
- Event Berlin (Veranstaltung Berlin), 1980 (Box 81)
- Board of directors meetings (Vorstandssitzungen), 1982
- Donor correspondence (Korrespondenz Spender), 1985 (Box 82)
- Correspondence (Korrespondenz), circa 1980s
- Board of directors meetings (Vorstandssitzungen), 1979-1981
- Federal committee (Bundesausschuss), 1972-1974 (Box 83)
- Board of directors circulars (Vorstand Rundschreiben), 1972-1974
- Konrad Adenauer Foundation (Konrad-Adenauer-Stiftung), 1985-1986 (Box 84)
- "Citizens action school" ("Bürgeraktion Schule"), 1986
- Press conferences (Pressekonferenzen), 1984-1985
- German Press Agency (Deutsche Presse-Agentur), 1992
- German Press Agency (Deutsche Presse-Agentur), 1992-1994 (Box 85-86)
- Study paths (Studiengänge), circa 1980s (Box 87)
- College teachers union (Hochschullehrerbund HLB), 1987
- Correspondence (Korrespondenz), 1979-1983
- 10th anniversary of Bund Freiheit der Wissenschaft (10 Jahre BFW), 1980
- Correspondence (Korrespondenz), 1979-1983 (Box 88)
- Federal committee (Bundesausschuss), 1974-1978
- Correspondence; (Korrespondenz), 1979-1983 (Box 89)
- "Consent" ("Zustimmung"), 1970-1971 (Box 90)
- Board of directors and federal committee meetings (Vorstands- und Bundesausschuss-Sitzungen), 1972-1975
- Board of directors circulars (Vorstand Rundschreiben), 1975 (Box 91)
- "Consent" ("Zustimmung"), 1970-1971
- Overload situation (Überlastsituation), 1988-1992
- Overload situation (Überlastsituation), 1988-1992 (Box 92)
- Brandenburg University (Universität Brandenburg), 1991-1995
- Magdeburg University (Universität Magdeburg), 1991-1995
- University endowment (Stiftungsuniversität), 1988-1993
- Rostock Greifswald, 1990-1995
- Press releases (Presse), circa 1990s (Box 93)
- Length of school day, duration of study (Schulzeit-Dauer, Studiendauer), circa 1990s
- BFW Pressespiegel, 1972 January 21-23
- BFW Pressespiegel, 1972 April 7 - 1972 July 27 (Box 94)
- BFW Pressespiegel, 1972 December 22-1974 January 10 (Box 95)
- BFW Pressespiegel, 1974 May 5 - 1975 Janaury 6 (Box 96)
- BFW Pressespiegel, 1975 July 16 - 1976 January 3 (Box 97)
- BFW Pressespiegel, 1976 July 12 - 1977 January 3 (Box 98)
- BFW Pressespiegel, 1977 June 30 - 1978 January 4 (Box 99)
- BFW Pressespiegel, 1978 July 5 - 1979 January 5 (Box 100)
- BFW Pressespiegel, 1979 July 11 - 1980 January 8 (Box 101)
- BFW Pressespiegel, 1980 July 2 - 1981 January 14 (Box 102)
- BFW Pressespiegel, 1981 July 2 - 1982 January 4 (Box 103)
- BFW Pressespiegel, 1982 June 30 - 1983 January 12 (Box 104)
- BFW Pressespiegel, 1983 July 4 - 1984 January 8 (Box 105)
- BFW Pressespiegel, 1984 July 2 - 1985 January 6 (Box 106)
- BFW Pressespiegel, 1985 June 1 - 1986 January 17 (Box 107)
- BFW Pressespiegel, 1986 June 30 - 1987 January 1 (Box 108)
- BFW Pressespiegel, 1987 July 5 - 1989 October 30 (Box 109)
- BFW Pressespiegel, 1990 May 5 - 1991 August 19 (Box 110)
- BFW Pressespiegel, 1991 November 26 - 1993 August 26 (Box 111)
- BFW Pressespiegel, 1997 May 29 - 1999 January 30 (Box 112)
- BFW Pressespiegel, 1995-1998 (Box 113)
- BFW Pressespiegel, 1999 March 16 - 1999 August 3 (Box 114)
- Brochures (Brochüren), 1970-2001
- Members (Mitglieder) (Box 115-120)
  General note
  CLOSED
- Tübingen section: Policy (Sektion Tübingen: Politik), 1974-1977 (Box 121)
- Lawsuits (Prozesse), 1976
- Marburg Union- Bund Demokratischer Wissenschaftler ( Marburger Bund, BDWi), 1977
- Miscellany (Verschied), 1973-1992
- Tübingen section: Miscellany, strike, Leaflets, Office (Sektion Tübingen: Verschied, Streik, Flugblätter, Büro), 1973 (Box 122)
- Tübingen section: Office, Members, Subscriptions (Sektion Tübingen: Büro, Mitglieder, Beiträge), 1971-1980 (Box 123)
- Bremen section: By-law, Circulars, Correspondence; Cologne section; FU Berlin Presseschau, (Sektion Bremen: Satzung, Rundschreiben, Korrespondenz; Sektion Köln; FU Berlin Presseschau), 2000 (Box 124)
- FU Berlin Presseschau, 2000-2001 (Box 125)
- FU Berlin Presseschau, 2001 (Box 126)
- FU Berlin Presseschau, 2002 (Box 127)
- Finances (Finanzen) (Box 128-135)
- BFW pamphlets, 2002-2009 (Box 136)
- BFW Organization: Office report (BFW Verein: Amtsgericht), 1972-1979
- BFW Organization: Charitable donations (BFW Verein: Gemiennützigkeit), 1972-1987
- BFW Organization: Financial office Bonn, Work reports (Verein: Finanzamt Bonn, Arbeitsberichte), 1977, 1978, 1981
- BFW Organization: Register of the organization (BFW Verein: Vereinsregister), 1975-1987
- BFW Organization: Meetings, various versions (Verein: Satzung, verschiedene fassungen), 1989
- BFW Organization: Bonn office, diskettes. Board of directors, federal committee, press reviews, donors, general addresses, press, invitations to forums and lectures (BFW Verein: Büro Bonn, Disketten. Vorstand, Bundesauschuss, Pressespiegel, Spender, allgemeine Adressen, Presse, Einladungen zu Foren und Vorträgen), 1984 (Box 137)
- BFW Organization: Work reports (BFW Vereing: Arbeitsberichte), 1984-2000
- BFW Organization: Board of directors circulars (BFW Verein: Rundschreiben an Vorstand), 2000-2005
- BFW Organization: Work reports (BFW Verein: Arbeitsberichte), 1984-2001
- BFW Organization: Dates and statistics (BFW Verein: Dateien und Statistiken), 2000-2004
- BFW Organization: Chronoligical circulars (BFW Verein: Rundschreiben chronologisch), 2001-2003
- BFW Organization: Circulars (BFW Verein: Rundschreiben), January 2004 - January 2006 (Box 138)
- Board of Directors: Correspondence (Vorstand: Korrespondenz), 1990-1992
- Board of Directors: Correspondence (Vorstand: Korrespondenz), 1992-1994
- Board of Directors: Correspondence (Vorstand: Korrespondenz), 1994-1996 (Box 139)
- Federal Committee: Correspondence (Bundesausschuss: Korrespondenz), 1990-1992
- Federal Committee: Correspondence (Bundesausschuss: Korrespondenz), 1992-1994 (Box 140)
- Federal Committee: Correspondence (Bundesauschuss: Korrespondenz), 1994-1999
- Meetings: Meetings of the board of directors (Sitzungen: Sitzungen Vorstand), 1974, 1979-1996 (Box 141)
- Meetings: Meetings of the federal committee (Sitzungen: Sitzungen Bundesausschuss), 1979-1996
- Meetings: Meetings of the board of directors, with related correspondence (Sitzungen: Sitzungen Vorstand, mit Korrespondenz), 1988-1991
- Meetings: General meetings, with related correspondence (Sitzungen: Mitgliederversammlungen mit Korrespondenz), 1992-1999 (Box 142)
- Meetings: Revenue/Expenditures, Resolutions, Bonn office move (Sitzungen: Einnahmen/Ausgaben, Auflösungsfrage, Büroverlegung Bonn), 1997-2004
- Meetings: Meetings of the board of directors (Sitzungen: Sitzungen Vorstand), 1996-2001 (Box 143)
- Meetings: General meetings (Sitzungen: Mitgliederversammlung), 2000-2004
- Meetings: Meetings of the board of directors (Sitzungen: Sitzungen Vorstand), 2004-2005
- Meetings: General meeting (Sitzungen: Mitgliederversammlung), 2000-2004
- Meetings: Board of directors, meetings with correspondence (Sitzungen: Vorstand, Sitzungen mit Korrespondenz), 2001-2007
- Meetings: Meetings of the federal committee (Sitzungen: Sitzungen Bundesausschuss), 1993
- Meetings: Regionalrepresentatives, meeting with correspondence, (Sitzungen: Regionalaufbetragte, Sitzung mit Korrespondenz), 2004
- Meetings: General meeting (Sitzungen: Mitgliederversammlung), 2006, 2008
- Meetings: Meetings of the board of directors (Sitzungen: Sitzungen Vorstand), 2006-2008 (Box 144)
- Meetings: General meeting (Sitzungen: Mitgliederversammlung), 2006, 2008
- Legal: Cromme (Prozesse: Cromme), 1993-1994
- Legal: Denes (Prozesse: Denes), 1996-1998
- Members (Mitglieder) (Box 145-154)
- Bonn Office, Personnel: Colonia insurance (Büro Bonn, Personal: Versicherung Colonia), 1976-1986 (Box 155)
- Bonn Office, Personnel: Society for the Promotion of the Bund Freiheit der Wissenschaft (Büro Bonn, Personal: Gesellschaft zur Förderung BFW), 1987
- Bonn Office, Personnel: Applications for employment (Büro Bonn, Personal: Arbeitsverträge), 1984-1999
- Bonn Office, Personnel: Applications for rent (Büro Bonn: Mietverträge), 1988-1992
- Bonn Office, Personnel: Financial office (Personnel) (Büro Bonn, Personal: Finanzamt (Personal)), 1990-1999
- Bonn Office, Personnel: Allegemeine Ortskrankenkasse (Büro Bonn, Personal: AOK), 1990-1999
- Bonn Office, Personnel: Barmer Ersatzkasse (Büro Bonn, Personal: BEK), 1990-1999
- Bonn Office, Personnel: Various (Büro Bonn, Personal: Verschienes), 1987-1999
- Bonn Office, Various: Hamburg-Mannhaeim insurance (Büro Bonn, Verschienes: Versicherung Hamburg-Mannheimer) (Box 156)
- Bonn Office, Various: Administration (Büro Bonn, Verschienes: Verwaltung)
- Bonn Office, Various: Various (Büro Bonn, Verschienes: heat, telephone, Colonia insurance, professional associations, electricity bill, removals (Verschiedenes (Heizung, Telefon, Versicherung Colonia, Berufsgenossenschaft, Stromrechnung, Umzüge))
- Bonn Office, Various: Subscriptions to the newspaper Freiheit der Wissenschaft (Büro Bonn, Verschienes: Abonnements Zeitschrift Freiheit der Wissenschaft)
- Bonn Office, Various: Address management (Büro Bonn, Verschienes: Adressenverwaltung), 1999
- Bonn Office, Various: Suppliers invoices (Büro Bonn, Verschienes: Lieferantenrechnungen), 1992 (Box 157)
- Bonn Office, Various: Resolution (Büro Bonn, Verschienes: Auflösung), 1999
- Bonn Office, Various: EDV support (Büro Bonn, Verschienes: EDV betreuung), 2002-2009
- Bonn Office, Various: Electricity bills (Büro Bonn, Verschienes: Stromrechnung), circa 2000s (Box 158)
- Bremen: Registration, reservations (Bremen: Anmeldungen, Reservierten), 1982
- Finances (Finanzen) (Box 159-178)